Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
The second and third Ashino Lakes,
I hope there won't be any more of those.
I received a complaint from
Chairman Kiel about the delay.
It came directly to me.
He was pretty upset.
He even hinted at dismissing you.
Adam is proceeding well,
and the Eva Project has begun work
on the dummy plugs.
What do the old men of Seele
have to complain about?
The all-important Human Instrumentality Project
is behind schedule.
All the projects are linked.
There are no problems.
Including Rei?
Well, never mind.
By the way, what should we do about that man?
We'll leave him to his own devices.
The same with the Marduk Institute.
I suppose we'll let him work to our purposes
for a while longer.
KYOTO
What started here, sixteen years ago?
EPISODE 15
LIES AND SILENCE
It's me.
Yes, so it is.
Shannon Bio, a chemical firm
funded from overseas.
It's been here for nine years,
but it also hasn't changed in nine years.
The Marduk Institute has
108 affiliated companies.
106 of them turned out to be
dummy corporations.
And this is the 107th?
This is the corporate registration.
You want me to take a look
at the board of directors, right?
Gendo Ikari
Kouzou Fuyutsuki
Kiel Lorenz
So you already knew about it?
The names are all familiar.
The Marduk Institute is supposed to be
an advisory body
controlled by the Human Instrumentality
Committee to select Eva pilots.
What it really does is not clear.
Your duty is to investigate Nerv.
Getting involved in the Marduk Institute
is a bad idea.
Well, I'm the type that has to see
everything for myself.
Hi, this is Kaji. I'm out right now.
Please leave your name and message.
Help me, Mr. Kaji! Don't touch me, you pervert!
Not.
What's going on?
Well, tomorrow's Sunday.
So I called Mr. Kaji, thinking that I'd get him
to take me out somewhere, but he's not in.
He's always out lately, no matter when I call.
That means you're free tomorrow, right?
Regrettably, yes.
Then I have a little favor to ask of you.
Well, it's like this...
What?! A date?!
A friend of my big sister Kodama
is insisting that I introduce you to him.
Please!
Head!
Get to it!
I'm sorry.
YOU need to get to it and clean!
Necrosis operation complete.
Graph measurement complete.
What are you going to wear tomorrow?
Synch rate is normal.
Oh, to the wedding?
I wore the pink suit for Kiyomi's wedding,
and the dark blue dress for Kotoko's
just the other day.
What about the orange one?
You haven't worn that one lately, have you?
Well, there's a reason for that.
It's too tight?
Yeah, so what?!
Should I get a new one on the way home?
It's an extra expense.
We've been invited to so many weddings lately,
the cost of all the gifts is starting to add up.
Everyone's just rushing to get married
before they're thirty.
No one wants to be the last one still single.
That's enough, you three.
Good work.
All these stupid tests are boring!
By the way, Shinji looks even more
downcast than usual today.
That's because of tomorrow.
Yes, tomorrow.
Tomorrow, I have to see my father.
What should I talk to him about?
Why do you ask me?
Because I once saw you
talking happily with him.
Say, what kind of person is my father?
I don't know.
I see.
You've been looking at me all afternoon
because you wanted to ask me that?
When we were cleaning today,
you were wringing out the cloth, remember?
The way you did it was like a mother.
A mother?
I thought it was like a mother.
Maybe you'd be really good
at being a housewife, Ayanami.
What are you saying?!
What do you mean? You're the one
that wanted to break up!
I'm home.
Welcome back.
I was wrong. I wasn't thinking back then.
You'd better go to bed.
Aren't you going on a date tomorrow?
What are you saying at this late date?
Yeah, with a hunk.
I don't know about you,
but I'm a different person now!
Hey, that's right, let me use
your lavender perfume!
But I still love you!
Absolutely not.
Jeez, cheapskate!
Time and people are two things that can't be
turned back to the way they were!
It's not for kids.
Is Shinji in his room?
I can never go back to the way I was!
He's been in there since he got back.
But I really do still love you!
It looks like he doesn't want to see his father.
I'm telling you, it's impossible!
If he doesn't want to, he should just say so.
I don't understand the Japanese.
It took me three years to forget you! It's too late!
Well, it's not that he doesn't want to.
That's the problem.
Leave!
Well done, Shinji.
Shinji?
I'm opening the door.
Are you scared? Of seeing
your father by yourself?
You can't keep running away.
Unless you take that step forward,
nothing will change.
I know that!
You'll begin to realize,
after that first step, it's just as important
to keep going.
Anyway, go see him tomorrow
with your chin held high,
because you'll be seeing your mother too.
Well, good night.
Hey, you bought a new dress for tomorrow,
didn't you? Let me see!
Oh, you want to see?
It was expensive, you know.
Taste is more important than price.
I've got that down pat.
Did you pick based on Mr. Kaji's
taste and stuff after all?
I think not. Not anymore.
NEXT DAY
Well!
See you...
Later.
Place three bags in your heart...
Red, blue, and yellow...
Now let us proceed with the reception.
Mr. Ryoji Kaji
Ryo's late.
That idiot has never been on time
in his entire life!
For your dates, you mean?
He's always on time for work.
Hey, you two! You look
even more beautiful today.
I couldn't get off work in time.
As if you're not puttering
around the office all the time.
Not that I care, but couldn't you have done
something about that stubble?
Look, your necktie is crooked.
Well, thank you.
You two act like you're married.
Sounds good to me, Ritchan.
Like hell I'd take him.
It's been three years since the last time
we came here together.
I ran away then,
and haven't been back since.
It just hasn't sunk in that Mother is resting here.
I don't even remember her face.
Man survives by forgetting his memories,
but there are some things
a man should never forget.
Yui taught me about the irreplaceable things.
I come here to confirm that.
You have no pictures of her?
There are none left.
This grave is just a decoration too.
There's no corpse.
So, the teacher was right.
You threw them all away.
I keep everything in my heart.
That is enough for now.
It's time. I'm leaving now.
Father!
Um, I'm glad I got to talk to you today.
I see.
Not bad! I didn't know you played.
I've been studying since I was five,
and this is all I can do,
so I don't really have any talent.
Perseverance is power. I'm a little impressed.
I started studying because
my teacher told me to,
so I could have quit anytime.
Then why did you keep going?
Because nobody told me to stop.
I should have known!
You came back early.
I thought you'd have dinner too.
He was just so boring!
So, while he was waiting in line
for the roller coaster, I left.
That doesn't seem too nice.
Really, Mr. Kaji is the only real man around.
What're you saying after all this time?
I'm ducking out to the restroom.
Don't ditch me now!
High heels...
How many years has it been since
the three of us last drank together?
Isn't Misato drinking too much?
She's acting a little giddy.
And you drink some more to
keep your high spirits in check.
Or vice versa, today.
As someone who lived with her,
your words carry the weight of truth.
Well, I did live with her,
but that was before she started
wearing heels and things.
It was unimaginable when
we were back in school.
I was a brat too.
That wasn't really sharing a life.
It was just living together, playing house.
Reality isn't that easy.
Oh yeah, here. A cat souvenir.
My, thank you. You're very thorough.
Only with the ladies.
When it comes to work, I'm sloppy.
I somehow doubt that.
What about for Misato?
I lost once before.
I make a point of not fighting
when I can't win the battle.
I think you have a chance at victory.
What about you?
I make a point of not talking about myself,
because it's no fun.
Katsuragi's sure taking a long time.
Maybe she's fixing her make-up?
What were you doing in Kyoto?
Huh? That's from Matsushiro.
It's no use playing dumb.
Your fingers will get burned if you
get involved in this too deeply.
That's the advice of a friend.
I'll take it seriously,
but if I have to get burned, I'd rather be burned
while playing with fire along with you.
Shall I go buy you some fireworks?
Welcome back!
You haven't changed, have you, you player?
Of course I've changed. To live is to change.
Homeostasis and transistasis.
What are those?
One is a force for the status quo,
and the other's a force for change.
A living thing is something that has
both of these conflicting qualities.
Like men and women.
Well, I'll be leaving now.
I've still got some work to do.
Really?
Sorry to hear it.
Later.
Hey, Shin? It's me.
I'm drinking with Kaji right now.
Right, we're on the third after-party.
Yes... Okay, later.
Was it Misato?
Yes, she said she'll be late,
so don't wait up for her.
What? Don't tell me she's coming back
in the morning!
No way, she's with Mr. Kaji.
What are you, stupid? That's WHY!
You shouldn't be throwing up at your age.
So sorry I'm that age.
I guess we're both that age.
Damn right.
You're wearing heels now, after all.
Time's really flown.
Shave that stubble off.
Yes, Ma'am.
I'll walk the rest of the way. Thanks.
Kaji, do you think I've changed?
You've become more beautiful.
I'm sorry that I insisted on
breaking up with you.
When I said I fell in love with somebody else,
that was a lie. Did you know?
No.
It's just that I realized
you were like my father.
That I wanted a man like my father...
When I realized that, I was afraid.
I was desperately afraid.
Of being with you, Kaji...
Of being a woman...
I was afraid of everything.
I hated my father, but fell in love
with someone just like him.
I chose Nerv, intending to
make a clean break with the past.
But even that was an organization
that Father used to belong to.
In the end, I've been fooling myself
by taking revenge against the Angels.
That was your decision, Katsuragi.
You don't have to apologize to me.
No, that wasn't a decision!
I was just running away.
Running away from the snare of my father!
I'm just like Shinji.
I'm a coward.
I'm really sorry. Telling you all this now
because I drank too much...
That's enough.
I'm such a child.
I have no right to tell Shinji anything.
That's enough!
On top of that, I'm an underhanded woman
that just clings to men when it suits me!
Even back then, I may have just been using you!
I hate myself!
That's enough! Stop it!
I'm so pathetic!
Hey, Shinji, do you want to kiss?
What?
A kiss. A kiss? You've never kissed, right?
Then, let's do it.
Why?
Because I'm bored.
Because you're bored?! But...
You don't want to kiss a girl on
the anniversary of your mom's death?
Afraid she may be watching you from Heaven?
Not really.
Or are you scared?
I'm not scared of a little kiss!
You brushed your teeth, didn't you?
Then, here I go.
Don't breathe, because it tickles.
Definitely not something to do to kill time!
All right, here we are. Hang on.
Mr. Kaji!
What?!
Well, I'll be leaving now.
Why don't you stay with us, Kaji?
I'd be laughed at if I went to work in this.
It'll be okay.
Hey, c'mon, Mr. Kaji...
Later.
He smelled of lavender...
Please take care of Katsuragi.
Sure.
Well, 'night.
Good night.
What's wrong? You look down.
It's because I kissed you!
Well, let me call the girl's roll. Ayanami...
NEXT DAY
Oh, Ayanami's absent again?
NERV HEADQUARTERS
DEEP UNDERGROUND FACILITY
CENTRAL AREA
CENTRAL DOGMA
2008 METERS UNDERGROUND
TERMINAL DOGMA
Hi, how's your hangover?
I'm finally sober now, thanks.
Glad to hear it.
Is this your day job, or your side job?
I wonder which?
Ryoji Kaji of Special Duty Organization Nerv's
Special Inspection Department...
Also, Ryoji Kaji of the Investigation Department
of the Japanese Ministry of Home Affairs.
So you know all about it.
Don't underestimate Nerv.
Is this an order from Commander Ikari?
My own discretion.
If you keep doing this other job, you'll die.
Commander Ikari is using me.
I can still keep going.
However, I will apologize for hiding it from you.
I'll call it even in thanks for yesterday.
Thanks very much, but...
The Commander and Ritchan are hiding
things from you too, and...
This is it.
This is...
Eva? No!
Impossible...
Yes, this is the origin and linchpin of
everything since the Second Impact.
This is Adam.
Adam? The First Angel is here?
You're right.
Nerv is deeper in this than I thought.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
The puffed-up Shinji gets swallowed
in a Sea of Dirac.
The short amount of time left to him
teaches him the meaning of despair.
Next episode: "The Sickness Unto Death, And..."
More fan service next time!
THE SICKNESS UNTO DEATH, AND...